

- Berlin, Germany
- vitalii.potapenko@gmail.com
- +49 176 214 76 461
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ vitalii-potapenko/
- https://github.com/vitaliiptp

## TECHNOLOGY STACK

HTML/CSS

JavaScript (React, NextJS, Storybook, NodeJS + Express); Python (Flask, Jupiter Notebooks); SQL (MySQL); REST APIs; Git, Unix VS Code, WebStorm, PyCharm

## PROJECTS

- Web application using NASA API
- Analysis of the dataset using SQL and IBM Db2 on Cloud
- Analysis of the Loan dataset using classification algorithms (KNN, Decision Tree, SVM, LR)
- Tweets sentiment analysis using Twitter API and AWS cloud computing

#### COURSES

- Databases and SQL for Data Science (IBM specialization)
- Machine Learning with Python (IBM specialization)

### LANGUAGES

English - Fluent German - B2 Russian - Native Ukrainian - Native

# VITALII POTAPENKO

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

After more than 8 years in financial analysis that included building dashboards, forecasts, and custom reports with Python scripting, I've decided to focus full time on software engineering. I've successfully completed the coding Bootcamp to structure and formalize my knowledge. And now I'm looking for a web developer position.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Sr Financial Analyst**

HERE Technologies GmbH, Berlin | Feb 2020 - Jun 2021

Conducted financial analyses
Improved reporting accuracy by
Supported financial planning

## Accountant

GetYourGuide GmbH, Berlin | Dec 2018 - Feb 2020

Set up controls to improve the accuracy of reporting
Saved costs by developing a price accuracy report
Controlled and reviewed inventory transactions
Posted and reconciled transactions in the general ledger and sub-ledgers

## Sr Financial Reporting Specialist

JSC Kyivstar (Veon Group), Kyiv | Sep 2012 - Sep 2016

Prepared analytical review of financial results
Increased efficiency by automated reporting process
Supported financial audits
Designed new KPI's

### **Financial Reporting Specialist**

JSC Ukrsibbank (BNP Paribas Group), Kyiv | Mar 2010 - Sep 2012

 Increased accuracy and reporting efficiency by implementing automation of fixed assets accounting in SAP FI • Optimized reporting procedures • Processed databases of bank transactions in MS Access using SQL

# **EDUCATION**

### Wild Code School Bootcamp

Full-Time Programm | Sep 2021 - Feb 2022 Full-Stack Web Development Program

### **EPAM University**

Course | Feb 2021 - Jun 2021 Full-Stack Web Development Program

## Free University Berlin

MA | Oct 2016 - Oct 2018

Social Sciences (Economics & Political science)

### **Kyiv National Economic University**

MSc | Sep 2004 - Jun 2009

**Business Administration**